Wang Xiaotao

<Senior Front-end Engineer>

Profile

Email: wxt2005@gmail.com Location: Kanagawa, Japan

GitHub: https://github.com/wxt2005 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/wxt2005

Summary

I'm a self-driven front-end engineer with over 7 years of experience in the development of complex web applications using React and Vue.

I have a passion for better user experience and love working with designers and discussing what's best for the user. I'm constantly chasing the new possibility of front-end technologies.

Also, I have an interest in improving development experience and performance. By making use of Node.js and server-side knowledge, I could help build better front-end infrastructure.

Experience

Rakuten UI/UX Engineer

December 2020 - Present | Tokyo, Japan

Vue, Nuxt, Node.js, Docker, Kubernetes

- Develop Rakuten GORA (Golf Booking) applications.
- Migrate legacy PHP pages to the new Nuxt application.
- Collaborate with designers to create design guideline and common components.
- Monitor and improve page performance for better SEO ranking.
- Audit page accessibility score, and ensure primary functions are keyboard accessible.
- Handle operations for front-end team managed servers and the deployment scripts.
- Designed and implemented the CDN release process.
- Migrated Nuxt applications to Kubernetes clusters.
- Improved CI/CD's performance and reduced cost by using dynamic agents on Kubernetes.

Cainiao Network Senior Front-end Developer

August 2017 - January 2020 | Hangzhou, Zhejiang, China

React, Redux, Node.js, Docker, MongoDB

- Built single-page applications for customer-oriented services.
- Migrated legacy payment service to React and released without any serious bugs.
- Introduced Jest for component unit testing, storybook for component management and Redux-Observable for better asynornous handling.
- Created team's front-end scaffold and constantly updated it to follow industry best practices.

- Designed and implemented an architecture that enabled several applications to share the same payment process.
- Collaborated with designers and created team's UI component library.
- Maintained front-end deployment system which can deploy applications by only several clicks.
- Implemented Word document conversion service for internal staff to publish online documents by one click.

DXY Front-end Developer

October 2014 - August 2017 | Hangzhou, Zhejiang, China

React, Redux, jQuery, Backbone, Node.js

- Led development team of 3 members to develop medicine database service.
- Refactored 3 legacy PHP + jQuery applications to React + Redux applications.
- Designed JSON schema for the server side to configure rendering of the page.
- Implemented forum rich-text editor image upload plugin.
- Implemented image compression function for mobile image upload.
- Worked with designers, standardized and implemented the company-wise prefecture and city selector component.
- Implemented and maintained all webview pages inside the company's mobile application.
- Collaborated with mobile engineers and designed JS bridge for the communication between native app and webpage.
- Created an internal library for opening native iOS or Android application from webpage.
- Deployed company's first private npm repository for internal package sharing.

Side Projects

Browser Opener

Swift, AppKit, CoreData

Browser Opener is a macOS application to help you open browsers based on URL.

As a front-end engineer, I use Chrome for debugging applications but use Safari for other kinds of stuff. It's painful to switch between browsers when opening different URLs, for example, localhost or 127.0.0.1.

Browser Opener is able to determine which browser to open when clicking links.

It started to support browser profiles in the latest version.

App Store: https://apps.apple.com/app/browseropener/id1387480496

Product Hunt: https://www.producthunt.com/posts/browseropener

Reading List

Swift, UlKit, Catalyst, CoreData

Reading List is an application for collecting web pages for later reading.

Most RIL applications require a user account and save data to their database. Also, their iPad supports are often incomplete. For instance, none supports drag and drop back then.

So I created my alternative. It's a universal application which supports iOS, iPadOS and macOS. All data is synced to iCloud and no user account is needed.

App Store: https://apps.apple.com/app/reading-list-read-later/id1501647738

Bangumi List

TypeScript, React, Redux, Node.js, Express, SQLite

Bangumi List is a Japanese anime information site.

Back in China, due to the fragmentation of copyrights, it was hard to check which anime is available on which video site. So I created this site to help Chinese anime fans to easilly watch their favorite anime series.

This site is also my playground for front-end technologies. It has been rewritten with different frameworks: plain HTML, jQuery, Angular, and React. Recently it's refactored to using TypeScript and added the login system.

Bangumi List: https://bgmlist.com

Source Code (GitHub): https://github.com/wxt2005/bangumi-list-v3

Skills

• JavaScript

CSS / Less / Sass / PostCSS

Vue + Vuex

- Semantic HTML
- React + Redux
- Node.js

Certifications

- JLPT N1
- TOEIC 950
- Qualification Certificate of Computer and Software Technology Proficiency Programmer
- Qualification Certificate of Computer and Software Technology Proficiency Software Design Engineer

Education

• B.E. Civil Engineering - Zhejiang Shuren University 2009-2013